Okay, so silver is on a roll. It's now
the second most traded precious metal in
the world just behind gold and a bunch
of you asked about this, so I'm going to
explain why. We actually use silver,
more silver than we can mine. And unlike
gold that mostly sits in vaults, it's
actually incredibly useful. It's the
best conductor of electricity on the
planet and it doesn't corrode easily.
This is a powerful combo and because of
this powerful combo, it ends up in
things like cars and smartphones and
data centers and solar panels and the
entire power grid. I mean, solar alone
is a huge one. We're making a lot of
solar panels lately and each of these
panels uses like a silver paste to pull
electricity out of the cell. Times that
by like a gazillion solar panels that
we're making and we're using a lot of
silver. And that's just one industry.
Silver is so versatile. It can be used
to make microscopic wires. It can be
flattened into sheets. It's super
reflective, so it's great for advanced
electronics. It's antibacterial and not
toxic, which makes it crucial for
medical equipment. And now AI is
exploding all of this. We need more
silver for data centers and for
microchips. Okay, so why don't we just
mine more silver? Well,
we don't actually mine silver. We mine
other things and as a byproduct, we get
silver. The supply of silver relies
[music] on a bunch of different
industries with different economic
dynamics. So, if you want to just mine
more silver, you don't do that. Okay,
but can we recycle the silver that we
use? Yes, we technically could, but
because we just use a tiny little
teaspoon of silver for all of these
products, we rarely actually put in the
effort to like go find it and melt
[music] it down and reuse it. So, silver
is kind of just disappearing into the
infrastructure that we're building. And
when you reduce the supply, the price
goes up and that's what's happening. But
this isn't new. Silver was like the OG
gold. Like, it was the first thing that
we used for currency before gold took
over. And like gold,
the reason why people are buying up
silver is because they feel insecure
about our financial system. They feel
like things are a little too topsy-turvy
right now, so they invest in precious
metals that they think will retain value
even as everything else kind of goes up
and down. But, what's weird about this
is how it is at once in vaults and in
factories at the same time. So, the rise
of value in silver is both an expression
of our fear and insecurity and our
technological advancement. Right now,
it's both.